Last week, we were asking people on the street all over downtown
Austin how much they made for a living, and then this happened.
I founded a company 20-something years ago and sold it
when I was 33, retired, and then went back to work.
How much did you sell it for?
Oh my gosh, that's amazing.
Amazing, right?
Glenn sold his company over 20 years ago,
retired, and then went on to travel the world.
He is now back to work creating a new startup, and he invited us to spend
a day with him to see what it's like standing in the shoes of a multimillionaire.
If you're new here, I'm James, and with
Jack and Josh, we're the School of Hard Knocks.
Every week, we talk to millionaires and share their
stories and advice with you all here on YouTube.
So subscribe if you're up for
that, and let's go meet Glenn.
Glenn, what's going on, man?
How you doing?
Hey, Glenn.
Great to see you.
Who is Glenn Boyd, and what's a little bit about
your story and where you got to where you are now?
Well, it's changed over the last 20-something years.
I primarily made my success and good fortune through
founding a tech company in the original dot com.
World.
So there's been a couple of iterations through the last 20-something years, but I founded a company
in the late 90s with a partner that was a good friend of mine at the time.
And we ended up taking the company public in 1999, and we were one of the
first dot com companies that were profitable and went public, and it was a big, big thing.
And then ended up selling it later in a merger with another public company
for, I think it was a billion, 30 million, what was the official sellout.
of the whole company in the transaction.
Retired, bought a yacht, traveled around the world for a few years,
spent a lot of time with my kids, and started getting bored.
And then only recently decided, well, I'd say recently in the
last five years that I more wanted to get back into tech.
And mostly because my kids are now all raised, and at least the
youngest one's off in college, and I've got plenty of time on my hands.
And boredom is a thing that you always have to overcome no matter
what, and there's only so many beaches you can go and hang out on.
Before you want to do something again.
Prior to starting a company, were you working corporate?
Like what were you doing before, and what kind
of led you to want to start a company?
Good question.
I've almost always been that way.
I started out very poor, actually in Texas,
roofing houses with my dad as a kid.
And later on, washing dishes
to help my mother pay rent.
And we ended up moving to
Southern California when I was 14.
Between that and becoming a busboy, I
started kind of dabbling with software and computers.
It was just getting started.
Wow.
In 1980.
Taught myself to program.
Was actually pretty good at it.
And pretty soon started getting contracting gigs.
And I was working full time at 16 years old.
Dropped out of high school.
Don't tell your parents that.
And went on to kind of found a couple of companies
as I was in my youth, 18 and 20 years old.
And then ended up working for another company
for my early 20s for a few years.
And one day woke up and decided if I'm going
to go for it, I have to do it now.
And decided to start my own company.
And that was 1991 or 2.
Yeah.
Traveling was one of my biggest passions.
I've been to about 20 countries.
For you, what has been the importance of traveling?
Oh, I think it's essential if you want to understand the
size of the world and you want to understand even markets.
I remember even traveling for business
and it gave me this perspective.
Like, wow, this is how big the world
is and how big the potential markets are.
Because it's so easy to get locked into
like, oh, I'm just focused on the U.S.
Or I'm just focused on a particular market.
But then you go to Hong Kong.
And you go to Shanghai.
And you go to New York.
Or if you go to Paris,
the world is a big, big place.
And I did quite a bit of
travel just setting up foreign sales offices.
Also lots of distributorships.
Then once I retired the first time, I did a lot of
travel just for fun to see the world and took my kids.
And my kids have traveled
all over the world as well.
Top three places that you recommend for people to go.
Well, it depends what your objective is, you know.
But I think everybody should go
see what's going on in China.
I mean, it's just unbelievable the size
and the scope of some of the cities.
Like Shanghai was such an impressive city.
I mean, my personal favorite, I
think I've been there too many times.
I need to deviate a little bit, is Italy.
I love Italy, but that's more
for personal and not for business.
The third one, I spent
a lot of time in Norway.
I had a, God rest his
soul, a dear friend that was Norwegian.
We've done lots of the fjords and just some
of the most amazingly beautiful part of the world.
Could you run us through what
your morning routine kind of looks like?
Well, it's pretty mundane.
These days, I've recently
just getting relocated into Austin.
First thing I try to do is make coffee.
I guess that's the biggest thing.
Once I get coffee started, I almost immediately jump on the computer
and see what my emails are that need to be responded to.
I make a lot of
to-do lists about this and that.
And sometimes I've got four
or five different things going on.
And I think the to-do list helped
me kind of organize through my days.
Because if you stay and do the same
thing all day long, it gets pretty mundane.
So I jump from different tasks and so forth.
So, so many things are done remotely these days.
And it's just electronic communication, you know.
That's at least how I get my day started.
And so when you're going through these tasks
and you're setting your priorities for the day,
how do you kind of segment what needs to
be done first and what's most important to do?
A lot of times it's about
doing the things I want to do.
It's easy to get into a procrastination where
you want to avoid those things you don't like.
I find that if I do something real easy
that I enjoy doing, it kind of breaks the ice.
And then I kind of get on a roll.
And if I tackle something immediately that I don't
really like, I kind of get on a roll.
If I tackle something immediately that I don't
And if I tackle something immediately that I don't
really like, I kind of get on a roll.
Well when something stuff I want to
do, there's a lot I want to do.
When I want to do something immediately that I
don't really like, I kind of get on a roll.
Oh, I typically do things with somesong.
certaines tasks, just sort of all theended timeinnally,
When I do something basically, I kind of only get combined into a
series of things and then I kind of go back and repair them,
And that's when I find myself wanting more and more.
You just, uh, don't realize
that casualties happen more often.
I know sometimes I stitch away my tasks.
next level and the next level. I'll bounce
from one task to another. Sometimes they're completely
unrelated.
What are your thoughts on cryptocurrency
and Web3 and the new blockchain developments
that are coming out?
Well, I definitely think there's going
to be a place in the
world for blockchains. They do have a purpose.
Most recent development is going to be interesting
to see how that plays out with Ethereum going
proof of stake versus proof of work. It's great
because it's no longer as intensive on
the environment, but whether or not the decentralization,
which is the whole reason you have
a blockchain, is going to stay decentralized. Decentralization
is, it's got its purpose because the whole
world is becoming decentralized. I mean, and we're doing
tons of Americans are hiring white collar
work remotely. So that's going to open up
opportunities for them to do that.
It's going to open up opportunities or it's
going to continue to need to have financial transactions
that are easy, fast, and not
necessarily have to go through government.
From a kind of software development perspective, what
have you seen kind of the changes having this
wave of Web3 come in for coders and programming?
I think the main thing behind Web3 is
people are frustrated with everything is advertising based.
Okay. And everybody's also, especially your
generation is waking up to privacy concern.
The boomers kind of came late
to Facebook, but then took it over.
But they don't seem to have any concerns
about privacy, whereas the whole next generation with
whether it's the millennials and now Z generation are
really not wanting their data held by one or two,
and they don't want their whole lives monetized via
advertising. And Web3 is really the first kind of
concept that comes along and says, hey, we're going
to provide a mechanism to do distributed types of
applications or distributed types of social interactions,
but not make them monetize via your personal
information. So in my opinion, I
think that's where the biggest Web3 stands.
Web3 stuff is going to land.
I kind of had a question for you because you had kind of
like brought it up and we were talking about this on a podcast
recently about how Grand Theft Auto, the game
got hacked, Uber got hacked, Binance, the cryptocurrency trading
platform. How crucial and important do you think is cybersecurity going
to be in the next 10 to 20 years with how
enhanced development is getting and people are hacking?
Like, how big do you think that industry is?
Like massive, massive.
I anybody who asks me like, oh, where should I start
in the tech world if I wanted to have a guaranteed career?
I tell them cybersecurity.
Information security, really.
It's just now starting to get into the mindset of CEOs and at all levels of
a corporation where security is thought about from the design of the product all the way up.
It's like we've built all these buildings without locks and doors
on them or so cheap that anybody can break into it.
And then all of a sudden we're shocked and surprised.
But it's hard. Security is hard and a lot
of people don't know how to properly build it.
You know, I kind of
started my career in information security.
So I'm considered 30 years ago an expert at it.
I used to train the FBI, the CIA, the IRS,
all these kind of guys on early days of information security.
When a, say, an agency, an IRS would go in and do a new bust on a company, it
used to be that they'd get file cabinets and they have all this information and they go through the files.
And then that's how they build their case.
Well, all of a sudden they were going in
and they do a bust and there's no file cabinets.
So there's a bunch of computers.
And they had all these agents.
They didn't know how to use these computers.
So early, early days was forensic science, which is being able to
show them how to recover deleted documents or recover information on the computer.
And that led into more
and more and more as in.
So cybersecurity is only going to get bigger and
especially now that everything is cloud based and everything's interconnected.
So I can pretty much get into
anybody else's network if it's open remotely.
So what does like a
typical workday look like for you?
So much of it is email.
I mean, I hate that, but
that's that's a big part of it.
I do a lot of the at
least right now because it's a new startup.
I'm doing a lot of the
architecting and a lot of the design.
So I'll kind of break between that and,
you know, do sketches and works on workflows.
And I'm a big believer in checking off list items.
So whatever that may be, you know, and because
it's early stage, so much stuff requires just communication.
And, you know, I take breaks.
I get out, do a hike.
There's a also really beautiful area on the 10th floor.
It's got, you know, so go down there and do
some work there and spread out on the big conference table.
Have you ever had like an idea for a company that
you were going to start, but it just like didn't work out?
Or you just put it away?
Well, I think the ideas are the easy part.
The doing is definitely hard.
And I have tons of ideas and I usually start and investigate
them and take them through like, OK, what would that be like?
And what's the viability of that?
And what's the competition of that?
And at different times, I've almost started stuff.
And then later something would happen either in my life that would derail
that or I would decide later just wasn't something I'm that passionate about.
You know, you dig into it.
It's a great idea, but it's
like, what if this is successful?
Do I really want to
do this for another five years?
No.
Pick something you want to be spending a lot
of time with because it's almost like creating a child.
You're going to be spending a
lot of time doing this thing.
It's going to take years for something successful.
Even the most successful companies usually
take three to five years minimum.
You've got to find something that you want to be
doing every day that doesn't bore you after a year.
Something that we've been kind of
like talking about today is, you know,
kind of like a business model.
Like your work life balance.
You know, we've talked a lot about it, like prioritizing your
health and how health is wealth and how important it really is.
Well, it's not just your mental health.
It's your physical health, especially tech.
And also with everything remotely working these days, I
can find myself working eight, 10, 12 hour stretches.
If I do that too many days
in a row, it also depletes my creativity.
Then I find myself just staring at the computer.
So that's why I break it up.
You know, I'll come down and use the
rec area and set up a little workspace.
I think this was kind of just different
than the way the work environment used to be.
Traditional office was didn't really,
you didn't work that way.
You were constantly engrossed with people or you
had conference rooms and you're constantly in meetings.
But now it's so much of is isolated.
You have to put yourself in a mental health space that
even though you're working alone, but you're also want to balance that.
As a business owner and for your first
company, what was the biggest challenge that you faced?
How did you overcome that?
Wasn't enough hours in the day.
Trying to raise young children and also trying
to start a business and run a business.
There just isn't enough hours in the day.
And that's.
That's tough.
I remember, you know, one particular day I probably had
eight, 10, 12 people lined out outside of my office.
So each one of them needed five, 10 minutes of
my attention and I'm taking them one at a time.
And then my wife at the time, it
calls and says, like, when are you coming home?
The kids are, you know, they're driving me crazy
because we had two young toddlers at the house.
And, you know, so it's
like he's trying to balance everything.
I guess what would you say is if people are looking to, you know, pursue a
great career, what industry do you think people should be really be looking into and exploring?
Well, I mean, I can.
Speak to things that I'm familiar with, and that's
the information security world is going to be massive.
It already is.
It's growing more.
It's not going to go away.
And there's not a lot of fields like that anymore.
I think it's a huge
opportunity for somebody who's starting young.
There's so many different directions you can go with it.
If you were given $100,000 and you were
told to start a company, what would you do?
Immediately, you would probably want to start in a service industry and try to get some income coming
in, because with that kind of level of capital, you're not going to be able to immediately go into.
Building a high tech industry or if you've got the skill set, take
the year off of work and write it yourself or build it yourself.
You know, if you can do that, you know, I was fortunate
if I could do that at a young age, not everybody today can.
So that's would be investing in yourself.
What is your best kind of like financial advice to younger people during this time of like the recession or just in general, like
with kind of the economy not being in a great spot that you recommend to people kind of looking to do with their money?
I think the inflation.
Things interesting because it's worldwide.
It's not particularly just the US and so
much of it was a result of two things.
One was the pandemic and the supply chain disruption.
And the other one is, you know, corporate greed, which has been obvious that the
profits are up at a world time record and that's being translated into inflation everywhere.
So I think inflation is going to adjust a little bit, mostly because corporations are
not going to be able to be as greedy as they have been this past time.
And the supply chain is also
going to start to level up.
Are we headed into the recession?
Recessions?
I think it's going to only last a
couple of years and they can be painful.
But I think the mistake we always made and I've made this mistake myself is that
when it's happening, it feels like everything is so dire and it's never going to get better.
When it finally does get better, it's like the clouds just part and
you forget how bad it was or how bad you felt at the time.
It's almost like depression and vice versa.
You forget the good days when it was like,
oh, my God, it was so great last year.
And you think this thing
is going to go on forever.
The key is to remind yourself
that it's temporary and plan for that.
You know, that's why savings accounts.
Are good.
Also, don't go so dire.
I think it's an excellent time to start
a company when it goes into a recession.
Labor is cheaper.
You get people who want
opportunity, who want to work harder.
I will wait on doing a remodel
and I've done this before in my house.
I'll wait for a recession to happen.
Why does that happen?
Because, you know, I'm going to spend the
same amount of money or actually spend less money.
Recessions are not always a bad thing.
You if you've got the capital and you can spend
it and do it, that's a great time to deploy it.
How do you know when it's a
good time to buy into a certain industry?
I think the.
Same thing that I've always heard and I believe strongly stick to
what you know or learn something and learn really deep on it.
And I think so often people shotgun and when they hear about something, it's already
too late, you know, and and then they're running around doing this and this and this.
If you know, tech stick to tech.
If you know, sports and
the sports industry stick to that.
If you know, media stick to that.
If you find something that you're passionate about,
go really deep in it and learn that.
And I think you're going to be way more successful by sticking
to one thing and going deep in it and understanding the players there.
Guys, thank you so much for tuning in.
Glenn.
Thank you so much.
For having us.
We really enjoyed spending the day with you being able to
ask you questions, get your perspective on a lot of things.
It really means a lot to us and
just thank you so much for your time.
Absolutely.
It was really a pleasure.
You know, if you guys enjoyed today's video, make
sure that you leave us a like and subscribe.
We got tons of great content coming to YouTube soon
and we just can't wait to keep on delivering this content.